Guide to the Pete Hest North American Indian collection, 1930-2002.
Hest Pete, North American Indian collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pete Hest North American Indian collection, 1930-2002.
6507
Pete Hest 1922-2002,
4 cubic ft.
Photographs, printed material, publications, scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Promotional and educational published material, pamphlets, brochures, photographs, posters, scrapbooks and other material collected by Pete Hest, relating to the history and culture of Native Americans in the United States and Canada.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Promotional and educational published material, pamphlets, brochures, photographs, posters, scrapbooks and other material collected by Pete Hest, relating to the history and culture of Native Americans in the United States and Canada.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hest, Pete, 1922-2002,
Subjects:
Indians of North America.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of the Native American Collection. (NAC)
CONTAINER LIST
- Photographs
  - Color prints from Gunther Michelson, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hopi Snake Dancer circa 1900, copy print (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Onodaga - Chief F. Henhawk, Edson-Thomas, Chief George Thomas, Sky-Yah-Deh, Edson Thomas, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    b/w prints
  - Totem Village - Indian Lore, July 18, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Corndance, Onondaga Reserve, August 21, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Totem Village, Cooperstown, NY, June 15, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ha-Do-Ee - Chief Floyd Henhawk, Chief J. Cornplanter, Cayuga Village, Onondaga, NYS Fair, Craft shop, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Misc. colorprints, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Misc. b/w copy prints (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Corndance, Photographer Steve Woiler, August 14, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    b/w print
  - Chief HighEagle - Age 98- "Ogala" Sioux taken 1953, Concho, Oklahoma (Box 1, Folder 11)
    b/w copy print
  - Sky-Yah-Deh, Pete Hest, 1940, 1933 - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Strawberry Ceremony, Onondaga Reserve, NY, June 15, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chief Koon-Kah-Za-Chy addressing the council in sign language (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Photogravure
  - Unidentified Edward Curtis print (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified b/w negatives, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified ceremony, Auburn, NY, March 10,1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Green Corn Dance, 1955-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Chief Percy Raymond Smoke, inscribed, August 18, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Crow and Sioux artifacts, n.d (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified performance, Loew's Theatre, Syracuse, December 22, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Misc. prints, NYS Fair, Pete Hest, unidentified ceremonies and events, 1934 - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Misc. prints of artifacts from the "Indianer Museum Radebeul", Germany, and other artifacts, 1971 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    color prints
  - Pete Hest, 1930s - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 25)
    b/w negatives
  - Group and individual portraits of Native Americans, 1924-1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    b/w and color prints
  - Dr. Erl Bates giving address at the 150th Anniversary of the Battle of Chestnut Woods, Grahamnsville, NY 1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Portraits, 1949 - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    b/w portraits
  - Six Nation Meeting, Onondaga Reserve, 1953, N.Y.S. Fair 1952, Planting Ceremony 1953, other misc. prints, 1949 - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - N.Y.S. Fair, Totem Village, Cooperstown, NY, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Misc. portraits - Pete Hest, Native Americans, 1939-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Misc. portraits - Pete Hest, Native Americans, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Misc. portraits - Pete Hest, Native Americans, n.d (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Misc. portraits - Pete Hest, Native Americans, n.d (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Misc. portraits - Pete Hest, Native Americans, n.d (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Pete Hest, family and friends, Lake George?, n.d (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Philip Green, Albert Cusick, Melinda Johnson, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Taos, NM, John Kilhan and unidentified Native Americans, 1900-1920s (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Misc. notes on language, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Misc Prints - some identified, 1930s-1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Unidentified group portrait, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Prints misc., n.d (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Prints misc., 1935-1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - N.Y.S. Fair, 1956, photographer George MacKown (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Onondaga Reserve, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Green Corn Dance, Onondaga Reservation, August 21, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    color print
  - Hal Roach, Frank MacDonald's Picture, n.d (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Thunder Bird's troupe of Wild Indians, n.d (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Chief Thunder Bird amd his Wild Indians, Long Beach CA, n.d (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Tim McCoy captured by the Indians in Metro-Goldwyn Mayers "Sioux Blood"., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Chief William Red Fox - inscribed, October 5, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Mrs. Margaret Thomas, Irving Powless Sr., Ross Webster, George Thomas Jr. Pete Hest, October 4, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Edson Lee Thomas, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - William Eagle Shirt, So. Dak. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Buffalo Bill Show, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Chief Howard Sky, Grand River, Canada, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Ernest Pierce, Davis Green, George Thomas, Andrew Pierce, Jordan, NY 1934 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - E.H. Allen, Wm. Eagle Shirt, T.H. Inch, W.G. Brooks, ca. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Arron Pudrey, Seneca, Tonawanda (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Pete Hest, autographed 1938 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Pete Hest, June 15, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Chief John Big Tree 1922 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - William Eagle Shirt, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Dubaque, Iowa - Palace Studio ca. 1900s (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Frank Bald Eagle, Manderson, So. Dak., September 6, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Printed Material
  - Native American Indian postcards, 1907-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Native American Indian postcards, 1907-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Native American Greeting Cards, 1967-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Native American Calendars, 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Native American Fold Out Postcards, 1907-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Research Material
  - Articles, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1925-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1954-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1955-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Greeting Cards, 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Indians General, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Paper items - photocopies, 1821-1826 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Paper Items, 1950s-1960s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Paper Items, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Museums and Historic Sites, 1954-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Crafts, 1903-1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Crafts, 1935-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Arts and Crafts, 1959-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Calendars, 1955-1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters and Articles, 1947-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Folder Postcards, 1907-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Postcards, 1907-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Postcards, 1907-1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Printed Images, 1950s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Promotional Travel Items, 1923-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Publications
  - Misc. publications (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbooks, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks and oversized prints, posters and advertising (Box 6)